本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:aimie king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Is this it?
ここですか
It's locked.
鍵がかかっていますぞ
ここが常世の井戸
This is the Eternal Well?
Princess...
姫様
My lord?
藩主様
Princess Naa.
奈阿姫様
宗直か 久しいな
Munenao? It's been a long time.
お待ちしておりました　奈阿姫様
I've been waiting for you, Princess Naa.
懐かしいな
It's been a long time.
これは戦場の風だ
The winds I feel are winds of war.
親方様
My lord...
才蔵か
Saizou?
We have just reached the Eternal Well.
ただいま　常世の井戸に辿り着きました
The time has come for the
princess to regain her power.
ついに姫君のお力を取り戻す時が参りました
うん
Our king will be extremely pleased.
これで我らの王もお喜びになる
ですが　邪魔者が何人か
However, several stand in the way.
構わぬ  始末せい
I don't mind...
Eliminate them.
は
Yes, sir.
もういい
Enough.
貴様　最初から気づいていたな
You knew from the start, didn't you?
You smell like an insect.
貴様からは蟲ケラの匂いがする
Interesting.
面白い
My Life's Greatest Task
「わが生涯で一番のお勤め」
ちょっと　どうなってんのこれ
Hey, what's going on here?
さっびーな
It's freezing...
Frozen.
凍ってやがる
Welcome, everyone.
ようこそ　皆さん よくぞここまで辿り着きました
You've done well to make it this far.
You're pretty good.
お主らなかなかやるな
真田十傑蟲　由利　鎌之介
I am Yuri Kamanosuke,
of the Ten Crucifix Insects.
Ten Crucifix Insects
Yuri Kamanosuke
同じく　筧　十蔵
And I am Kakei Juuzou,
of the Ten Crucifix Insects.
Ten Crucifix Insects
Kakei Juuzou
さて　これ以上の口上は不要
Now then, there is nothing more to discuss.
全員まとめてかかってきなさい
All of you, come get me.
幸村様に仇なす者は全てこの私が切り捨てます
I shall kill any that would
oppose Yukimura-sama.
だそうだ
Yup.
でもま　できるだけ楽しんで行こうや
But let's have some fun first!
参る
Here I go.
Everyone, I'm sorry I'm late!
皆さん　遅くなって申し訳ありません
早すぎだよ　バーカ
You're too early, fool!
俺より先に手出すんじゃねー
Don't kill them before I get a chance!
She blocked it...
受け流しやがった
Tamekichi! Matsukichi!
為吉　末吉
鎌のじ　二人も増えたぞ
Hey, Kama, we have two more.
Full-Power Slap!
全力つっぱり
いやはや　式神使いか
An onmyoji?
This will be even more fun.
ますます楽しくなりそうだわい
I won't let you have any fun!
楽しませるつもりはないわね
悪いけど　私冷え症なの
Sorry, but I don't like the cold.
とっとと終わらせるから
I'll finish this quickly.
同じだな
Then we are similar...
寒いのが苦手なのも飛び道具の使い手であることも
We both dislike the cold and we
both used ranged weapons!
Very wrong, everyone.
大バツですよ　皆さん
無策で飛び込むなど思慮の浅い蟲達がすることです
Attacking without a plan is for thoughtless insects.
大岡殿
Oooka-dono!
奴らの戦力　能力はおおよそつかめました
I have a good grasp of their power and abilities.
脱皮をされる前に一気に片付けますよ
We will finish them
before they can shed their skins.
はい
Right!
これが常世の虫を退治した塵外刀か
So this is Jingaitou, the weapon
that slew the Eternal Insect...
Then you were once with the Insect Hunters?
貴様　元は蟲狩か
Why do the Insect Hunters serve the Shogunate?
なぜ蟲狩が幕府の犬となった
I've nothing to say to an insect.
蟲ケラに聴かせる話などない
You're weak!
弱者のくせに
The Insect Hunters...
蟲狩か
To slay the Insect Magistrate.
蟲奉行を抹殺すること
それが我らの悲願であり
That is our long-held dream,
and the final service we can
render to the friends we killed.
奴に殺された仲間達への弔いになる
任せろ
Leave it to me.
しくじるなよ　我が弟
Don't screw it up, my little brother.
よく来たな　蟲狩
Welcome, Insect Hunter.
You were waiting for me?
待っていたのか
Hatred leads to more hatred.
憎しみは次なる憎しみを生む
その連なった鎖を ここで断ち切るが良い
Sever the chain here.
良い覚悟だな
Then you are ready to die?
That blade can indeed kill me.
その刀なら　妾を殺す事も出来よう
少々長く生きすぎた この世に未練など無い
I've lived a little too long.
I've nothing left to bind me to this world.
What's wrong?
どうした
その瞳に嘘は無かった
There was truth in her eyes.
She was like me.
こいつは俺だった
誰からも愛されず　誰も愛さず
Unloved by anyone.
Loving no one in return.
ただ託された使命を全うする者が そこにいた
Only performing the task set before her.
That night, I left the Insect Hunters.
あの夜を限りに俺は蟲狩を止めた
貴様は弱者の中でも強い方だな
You're one of the stronger of the weaklings.
これは褒美だ　受け取れ
This is your reward... Take it!
不協壁音
Dissonant Noise!
俺は蟲ケラを退治できればそれでいい
If I can defeat the insects, that's enough!
塵外刀　鉏の型　飛水
Jingaitou: Rhino Form...
Flying Water!
塵外刀　大瀑布
Jingaitou: Great Waterfall!
Was that Mugai?
今の無涯の旦那か
それに　霧隠才蔵よ
And Kirigakure Saizou...
I knew he survived.
あいつ　やっぱり生きてたんだわ
無涯殿が戦っている
Mugai-dono is fighting...
自分も頑張らねば
I have to do my best, too.
What are you saying, Tsukishima-dono?
何を言っているんですか　月島殿
は
Huh?
無涯殿が居なくなったら　誰がお付きの方をお守りするのです
If Mugai-dono is gone, who will
protect the Magistrate's servant?
才蔵の奴　派手にやっておるの
Saizou's kicking butt...
But he revealed the way to break the barrier.
おかげてこの結界を破る方法を奴らに知られてしまいましたよ
少し急いだ方がいいでしょうね
We should hurry.
Oooka-dono, what do we do?
大岡殿　どうなさいますか
当然　お付きの方を優先します
Naturally, our priority is the servant.
Here we go, Juuzou!
行きますよ　十蔵
おーよ
Right!
任せて
Leave it to me.
今よ　2人とも
Now, you two!
月島殿　早く
Tsukishima-dono, quickly...
Flowering Wind-style Draw:
Divine Punishment!
花鳥風流居合い　天バツ
I understand.
なるほど
藩主様はこの階段を使ってこちらに入られたんですね
Then you descended these stairs, my lord.
宗直　早速ですまぬが　井戸の封印を解いてもらいたい
Munenao, I need you to break
the seal on the Well now.
江戸より話は聞き及んでおります
I've heard the situation from Edo.
なれど
However,
there's no way to know how the Well's
evil energy will affect you, Princess.
この井戸の瘴気は姫様にどのような害を及ぼすか計り知りませぬ
It's all right.
良い　そのために来たのだ
That is why we're here.
今妾が井戸に入り　力を取り戻さなくては
I must enter the Well and regain
my power or Kishuu...
この紀州藩　いや　この国の存続も危ぶまれよう
No, this very country will be in danger.
さようにございます
Very well.
Masachika! Move the rock atop the Well!
正近　井戸の石をどけるのじゃ
はっ
我が王の息吹
The breath of my king...
ついに常世の井戸が開く
At last, the Eternal Well opens.
I'm coming, miss!
お付きの方　今参ります
待っていてください
Wait for me!
What's wrong, Tsukishima-dono?
どうしました　月島殿
大岡殿
Oooka-dono, do you think Sanada Yukimura
この階段の上には真田幸村が待ち構えているのではありませんか
waits at the top of these stairs?
申し訳ございません　大岡殿
I'm sorry, Oooka-dono.
お付きの方の護衛は大岡殿お一人でお願いします
Please protect the servant on your own.
自分はこれより　真田幸村に戦いを挑んで来ます
I go now to challenge Sanada Yukimura!
That's wrong.
バツです 勝手な行動は許しませんよ
Do not be selfish.
しかし　幸村を倒せば　結果的にお付きの方をお守りすることになります
But if we defeat Yukimura,
that also means saving her.
あなたが負けたら どうなさるのですか
And what if you lose?
I shall continue to win until I die.
自分は死ぬまで勝ち続けます
いえ　もし敗れたとしても
No, even if I die, I'll at least slow him down!
きっと足止めになって見せます
自分が時間を稼いでる間に
While I buy time, you and the servant
can complete the mission.
大岡殿はお付きの方と共にお勤めを果たしてください
常にこの身は戦場にあり　これぞ常駐戦陣
I am prepared for a fight.
I am always ready for a fight.
That is the samurai's path my father taught me!
父上より学んだ武士の道です
奈阿姫様　改めて言うまでもないでしょうが
Princess Naa...
There's no need for me to remind you,
この事はあなた様に苦渋の選択を迫る事になるやもしれませぬ
but this may force you to
make a painful decision.
Here is what the ancient texts read.
古文書にはこうあります
汝　常世の井戸の封印を解く勿れ
"Do not break the seal on the Eternal Well.
Only those who have overcome their
painful pasts will recover their power."
悲しみの過去に打ち勝つ者のみ　力を取り戻すであろうと
敗れたら　消え去るのみか
Then if I fail, I shall simply disappear?
I believe so.
恐らく
井戸の力は強大です
The Well is quite powerful.
姫様の御心にある記憶は更なる過去に遡り
Your heart's memories will go
further back, into the past,
taking you to ancient times.
遥か太古の昔に連れ去ってしまうのでしょう
The distant past?
遠い過去か
That's fine.
構わぬ
What is this light?
なんですか　この光は
The Well has opened.
井戸が開いた
月島殿　最上階へは　私が行きます
Tsukishima-dono,
I shall go to the top floor.
あなたは　あの光の根元に居るお付きの方をどうかお願いいたします
I entrust you
with protecting the servant,
who will be at that light's source.
しかし　それでは
But then...
今まさに　お付の方がご自身のお務めを果たそうとしているのです
The servant is about to fulfill her task.
それは　あのお方のお命にかかわる最大の危機
And it will seriously threaten her life.
お付の方のお命が
Her life?
お付の方を必ず守ると約束したのは
You were the one who promised
to protect her, no matter what,
Tsukishima-dono.
月島殿　あなたでしょう
If you do not go now,
can you see your duty through?
こんな時に行かずして　お供の役が務まりますか
Very well!
分かりました
自分は光の元へ向かいます
I shall go to the light's source!
So, Oooka-dono, please defeat Sanada!
ですので　大岡殿は見事真田を打ち取ってください
よき判断です　月島殿
That is the right decision, Tsukishima-dono.
蟲奉行様は　あなたに守られたいと願っているのです
The Insect Magistrate wishes
for you to protect her.
その思いに応えてあげてください
So please do it.
To me, the samurai's path
私にとって武士の道とは
将軍吉宗様より与えられた命を全うするもの
is following the orders that
Shogun Yoshimune gives me.
お務めに私情を差し挟むなど決して許されぬ
I do not allow my feelings
to interfere with my duty.
粛々と此度のお務めも　いつも通りに果たすはずでした
I'd planned to complete this job like any other.
そうは言っても　この情況はまったくバツです
And so, this situation is very wrong.
This will be the greatest task
大岡越前守忠相
これは　わが生涯で一番のお務めと　なりそうですね
in the life of Oooka Echizen no Kamitadasuke.
よいのかな
Are you sure about this?
姫君が井戸に入ってしまうぞ
The Princess is entering the Well.
わしの相手をしている場合ではなかろう
You have no time to waste on me.
もっとも　貴様はわしから逃れられんがな
Though, of course, you cannot escape me.
Potato-boy?
芋坊主
Take care of her!
任せたぞ
What's happening, Masachika?
どうした　正近
しょう　瘴気の毒が
Th-The poison in the Well...
宗直　お主達にこれ以上は無理じゃ
Munenao, you cannot remain here any longer.
わらわだけで行く
I shall go alone.
ひ　姫
P-Princess!
宗直様　お止めください
Stop, my lord...
Staying here is dangerous!
これ以上は危険です
Insect Magistrate...
蟲奉行様
ネズミよ　まだわが家臣達の全員を倒していないようだが
It seems you have yet to defeat my men, rat.
あなたこそ　大将自らが階下に下りては
And if you were to go down there now,
家臣達の面目を潰すことになりますよ
you would rob your men of
their chance for glory.
よかろう　少しだけ相手をしてやる
Very well.
I shall fight you for a short while.
初手は貴様に譲ってやるぞ
You may make the first move.
どうした　困難か
What's wrong?
Are you not coming?
なればこちらから参るぞ
Then I shall come to you.
花鳥風流居合い　天バツ
Flowering Wind-style Draw:
Divine Punishment!
そう来なくてはな
That's what I was hoping for...
すまんな　加減を間違えた
Apologies, I didn't intend to hit so hard.
これほどまで力の差が
He's so much stronger than I am...
さて　二の手は気張って来いよ
Now, time for your second move.
Wh-What's this?
こ　これは
It stinks...
くせぇ
すまんのう わしの体躯はカメムシなのでな
Sorry.
I have the body of a stink bug.
それでの　この毒ガスは火気厳禁なんだ
And you'd best keep fire away
from this poison gas...
相性がよすぎるからな
It's quite flammable.
Time for some fun!
一つ派手に参ろうか
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi... Tamekichi!
Get back, kiddo!
坊ちゃん　下がれ
Stop messing around, guys.
しっかりしなさいよ　あんた達
You can't escape this!
こいつからは逃げられんぞ
If I enter this light, my powers will return.
この光の中に行けば　わらわの力が取り戻せるというのに
前に進めぬ
But I cannot go forward.
I cannot move forward...
どうしても　前に進めぬ
お付の方
Miss!
月島
Tsukishima?
Tsukishima...
月島
ご無事ですか　お付の方
Are you okay, miss?
うむ　よく来てくれた
Yes.
Thank you for coming.
今の間合いはよかったぞ
That was an excellent attack.
今の一振りで どれだけの時間が稼げただろうか
How much time did that attack buy?
半時？一刻？
An hour? A minute?
それとも　瞬きするほどの一瞬か？
Or perhaps under a second?
だが次の手が遅い
But your next attack is too slow.
それではこの俺に勝てぬぞ
You cannot beat me like that!
It's over, then?
終わりか
But it was an amusing way to pass time.
だが　暇つぶしにはなったぞ
Not yet...
まだです　実にバツですね
That's quite wrong.
相手の力量を見くびりすぎです
You've underestimated your opponent.
このお務めは　蟲奉行様が本来の力を取り戻すことによって終わる
My task ends when the Magistrate
recovers her full power.
それはすなわち　蟲奉行様が己の毒により
And that means her poison will
never let her touch another.
もう二度と誰にも触れられず
Or allow them to touch her...
誰にも触れることができなくなるということ
私は幼い頃　蟲奉行様をお見かけしたことがある
I saw her once, when I was young.
蟲奉行様は幕府にとって 蟲を追い払ってくれる単なる道具
To the Shogunate, she was a mere
tool for keeping the insects away.
Like a doll without a heart.
まるで心のない人形であった
他者の行く末など　まるで興味がない如く振舞われ
She acted as though she didn't care
for anyone else in the world.
そんな己の宿命をも受け入れているご様子だった
She seemed to accept her fate.
あのお方はずっと変わらなかった
She never changed.
お姿も　あの儚げな目も
Neither her appearance,
nor her empty eyes.
だが　此度の道中で見たお姿は
But when I saw her during this journey,
強く　気高く　優しく
she was strong, noble and kind...
私などより遥かに血の通ったお方に変わったおられた
She had become someone
far more human than myself.
思い出は作っておきたくてな
I wished to make some memories.
私は決心した
I resolved then
あのお方の思いを　守って差し上げたいと
that I would protect her feelings.
So each time I swing this blade,
だから　私がこの方のお一振りするたびに
蟲奉行様と月島殿が　共にいる時を増やすことになる
it buys more time for her
to be with Tsukishima-dono.
たとえ　それが僅かな時間でも
Even if it's for a short time...
ほんの僅かでも　増やすことは叶うなら
If I can ensure it lasts even
a brief while longer, I...
私は
I shall continue to swing my sword!
この刀を振り続ける
今のは少々骨があった
That was a little better.
褒めてやるぞ　居合いの武士
Accept my compliments, samurai.
But cease your useless struggles!
だが　悪あがきも大概にしろ
大岡殿　聞こえますか
Oooka-dono, can you hear me?!
お付の方は無事です
The servant is safe!
ここからは　自分がお守りいたします
I will protect her from now on, Oooka-dono!
大岡殿
月島　殿
Tsukishima-dono...
That was right... Tsukishima-dono.
マルですよ　月島殿
So he died with a smile on his face?
笑いながら死んだか
来るな来るな
Stay away!
Okay...
よっしゃ　懺斬り
Repentance Slash!
Got you!
覚悟
やった
Did we get them?
こいつら
They...
まだ死んでない
They aren't dead yet.
これは　何でしょうか
What is this?
この井戸の水は　猛毒じゃ
The water of this Well
is extremely poisonous.
人が入れば　その毒に苦しむ　もがいながら死んでゆく
If humans enter, they will suffer,
screaming, before dying.
だが　蟲が入れば
But if an insect enters,
they will attain a powerful body,
強靭な体躯を手に入れ　無敵な存在となるのだ
becoming invincible.
Huh?
もう分かったであろう
You understand now, right?
わらわがこの中に入るということの意味を
What it means if I enter it like this.
一見の時に隠さず話すべきであった
When we first met, I should
have told you everything.
あの後　八丈島の時
And afterward, at Hachijo Island...
この紀州への道中の間
And again, on the way here to Kishuu...
何度も何度も言おうとしたが　言えなかった
I tried to tell you again and
again, but I could not.
すまぬな　お主との関係が 愉快で仕方なかったのだ
I'm sorry.
I loved being with you so much.
隠すとは？一体何のことですか？
What do you mean by tell me everything?
わらわにはいくつかの肩書きがある
I have several titles.
その中の一つがお主にとって　とても大事なものなのだ
One of them is quite important to you.
わらわは蟲奉行のお付の方ではなく
I am not the Insect Magistrate's servant.
I am the real...
本物の…
姫
Princess!
ようやくお目覚めの時が参りましたな　姫君
So the time of your awakening
has finally come, Princess.
真田幸村
Sanada Yukimura!
Next Time
井戸に入るなら胸に大きく息を
Before you enter the Well, take a deep
breath and puff out your chest.
こうか
Like this?
いいえ
No.
こうか
Like this?
いいえ
No...
おかしい　なぜ胸が膨らまない
It doesn't make sense.
Why isn't her chest sticking out?
うるさい
Shut up!
次回　蟲奉行「蟲奉行　呪われし過去」
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
The Insect Magistrate's Cursed Past
The Insect Magistrate's Cursed Past.